Guide to the Park Poultry Producers Association Records 1923-1941
Montana State University-Bozeman Library
Park Poultry Producers Association Records
1923-1941
Montana State University Library, Merrill G. Burlingame Special Collections P.O. Box 173320 Bozeman, MT 59717-3320 United States Phone (406) 994-4242 Fax (406) 994-2851 http://www.lib.montana.edu/archives/ University Archivist spcoll@www.lib.montana.edu
Collection 0027, MtBC, us
Park Poultry Producers Association
.8 linear feet
The Park Poultry Producers Association Records consists of financial records; order sheets; sales records; producer contracts; correspondence; minutes (1923-1924); articles of incorporation and association; bylaws; membership lists; materials from U.S. Dept. of Agriculture giving instructions for killing, dressing, and shipping turkeys; and sales lists (1930-1937) for the Northwest Turkey Growers Association. Persons represented include Earl Sexton and John Nickelson, association managers in the 1930s.
Historical Note
The Park Poultry Producers Association was a turkey growers association in Park County from 1923-1940. The Association was formed in 1923 to develop and carry on a county program of work for the development of the poultry industry. The Association had the goal of putting on a poultry show to educate what constitutes good poultry and to promote the better sale of live poultry through cooperative selling. Earl Sexton became manager of the PPPA in 1931 and was replaced in 1937 by John Nickelson. Most of the correspondence is addressed to Nickelson. The reason for the disappearance of the PPPA after December of 1941 is unknown.
The Park Poultry Producers Association (PPPA) records include various business records including financial records, order sheets, sales records, producer contracts and correspondence from 1923-1940. Most of the correspondence is addressed to either Earl Sexton or John Nickelson, two PPPA managers during the 1930s. The records also include correspondence from the United States Department of Agriculture through pamphlets and letters giving instructions on how to kill, dress, and ship turkeys. Extensive sales lists are included for the Northwest Turkey Growers Association from 1930-1937. The records include the PPPA's Minute Book from 1923-1924, written in a Park County grade school notebook, that lists the Articles of Association, membership lists, and lists for grades of turkeys. Three unique items are a letter written in 1940 from a customer demanding to know what happened to the settlement for his turkeys, several copies of a poem and song about turkeys, and a brass plate that reads: "Park Poultry Producers Association, Livingston, Mont." Other papers include John Nickelson's inspectors' license from the USDA for dressed turkeys, a diagram for a turkey packing table, and an Articles of Incorporation and By-Laws booklet. The collection has been arranged in topically labeled folders.
This collection is open for research.
The Park Poultry Producers Association collection was donated by Mrs. Wesley D'Ewart of Wilsall, Montana, circa 1964.
Nickelson, John; Sexton, Earl
Northwest Turkey Growers Association; United States.-Dept. of Agriculture
Turkey industry-Montana
Advertising and Marketing; Montana
- Park Poultry Producers Association: Minute Book, Articles of Association, membership list, list for grades of turkeys, 1923-1924 (Box-folder 1/1)
- Park Poultry Producers Association: Articles of Association; Smith Hughes Dept Park County High School's Instructions for proper slaughter and dressing of turkeys (Box-folder 1/2)
- Sales to Jerpe Commission Company, Omaha, Nebraska, November 1929 (Box-folder 1/3)
- Sales to Beatrice Creamery Company, Beatrice, Nebraska, December 1929 (Box-folder 1/4)
- Sales to Northwestern Turkey Growers Association, December 1930-January 1931 (Box-folder 1/5)
- Sales to Northwestern Turkey Growers Association, December 1931-January 1932 (Box-folder 1/6)
- Sales to Northwestern Turkey Growers Association, December 1932-January 1933 (Box-folder 1/7)
- Sales to Northwestern Turkey Growers Association, December 1933-January 1934 (Box-folder 1/8)
- Sales to Northwestern Turkey Growers Association, December 1934-January 1935 (Box-folder 1/9)
- Sales to Northwestern Turkey Growers Association, December 1935-January 1936 (Box-folder 1/10)
- Sales to Northwestern Turkey Growers Association, December 1936-January 1937 (Box-folder 1/11)
- Sales records (Box-folder 1/12)
- Park Poultry Producers Association: Financial statements, 1928; 1929; 1932; 1935; 1936 (Box-folder 1/13)
- Park Poultry Producers Association: Miscellaneous papers, 1931-1940 (Box-folder 1/14)
- Turkey producers contracts, completed forms and blank forms (Box-folder 1/15)
- Check Registers, Books 1-5, (1928-1929) (Box-folder 2/1)
- Check Registers, Books 6-10, (1929-1930) (Box-folder 2/2)
- Check Registers, Books, 11-15, (1930-1932) (Box-folder 2/3)
- Check Registers, Books, 16-20, (1932-1935) (Box-folder 2/4)
- Check Registers, Books 21-25, (1935-1936) (Box-folder 2/5)
- Check Registers, Books 26-30, (1936-1938) (Box-folder 2/6)
- Check Registers, Books 31-32; Deposit Book, (1938-1939) (Box-folder 2/7)
- Bank Statements, (1928-1930); (1939-1940) (Box-folder 2/8)
- Park Poultry Producers Association: Turkey Grade Instructions (Box-folder 2/9)
- Northwest Turkey Growers Association: By-Laws, Turkey Instructions and Financial Forms (Box-folder 2/10)
- Park Poultry Producers Association: Business Receipts and Correspondence (Box-folder 2/11)
- Park Poultry Producers Association: Brass Plate (Box-folder 2/12)